For most students
the weekend
represented two days of fun,
freedom, and
in the case of my brother
a chance to ignore
all forms of hygiene.
Come on! Come on!
To me however
it represented...
An unwelcome break
from education.
Whoo! Thank the Lord!
But this wasn't
a typical weekend
because this was the weekend
I got to do my parents taxes.
Howdy do, W-2.
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
*YOUNG SHELDON*
Season 02  Episode 04
Episode Title:
" A Financial Secret and Fish Sauce"
"If you were not covered
by retirement plan
but your spouse was,
see the worksheet on page14"
Try and stop me.
Mom, I was going
through our expenditures
and noticed
our grocery bills are up 12%
compared to last quarter.
Any idea why?
There's a person at the end of
the table that eats for free.
There's a person at the
other end of the table
that eats for three.
I've been buying groceries
for the church food drive.
I think that's it.
Ooh, I bet
I could write that off,
including the gas
it took to drive
to the grocery store
and then to the church.
With all that driving,
maybe she can count
her car as a home office.
Sounds aggressive, but I
like how you're thinking.
None of that is necessary,
it's for charity.
What's the point of charity
if there are no tax benefits?
Eat your peas.
I like
how he's thinking.
You eat your peas, too.
Dad, banking question.
What's that, buddy?
I noticed
there's a check missing.
I have a copy of check 128
and a copy of check 130,
but 129 isn't there.
Oh, yeah,
don't worry about it.
But I enjoy worrying;
I find it very relaxing.
'Course you do.
I balanced
the rest of the account,
and it appears to be
a check for $300.
All right, well,
let's just put it down
for $300 for miscellaneous.
I've never labeled anything
miscellaneous in my life.
I'll go ask Mom.
Wait.
I just remembered.
I gave the money to a friend.
- Who?
- It doesn't matter who.
Why'd you give it to them?
They needed it.
It... it's like charity.
Ooh, another write-off,
excellent.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
What do you say, we
keep this quiet?
You mean like a secret?
No, no, just, you know,
something between you and me.
What about Mom?
Mom is on
a need-to-know basis.
- What if Mom needs to know?
- Okay, it's a secret.
Just trust me.
It is better for everyone
if she doesn't know about this.
But I'm not good
at keeping secrets.
It's not hard.
Just keep your mouth shut.
But I'm not good
at keeping my mouth shut.
Sheldon,
all you got to do... is be cool.
"Be cool."
He might as well have asked
me to fly around the backyard.
- Good night, baby.
- Night, Mama.
- Love you.
- Love you, too.
Oh, hello.
I was just brushing
my teeth like I do every night.
Ah, ha!
Nothing new there.
You all right?
Yes. I'm cool.
I'm very cool.
Tell Sheldon
what cool means.
Hush.
Sweet dreams.
Love you.
Love you, too,
'cause you're my mom.
You're so weird.
More than usual?
No, I guess not.
Perfect.
To avoid looking suspicious,
I tried to interact with
my mom as little as possible.
Thankfully, it's rude to
speak with your mouth full.
You look tired, baby.
Sleep okay?
Mm-hmm.
So how big a tax refund
you think we're gonna get?
Mm.
- Mornin'.
I slept in the nude last night.
Felt every little breeze.
Thank you for sharing that.
You're welcome.
Fight, you cowards, fight!
You fight, Skeletor.
Mare, we got any batteries?!
Look in the drawer by
the refrigerator.
There was only so much food
I could eat,
so I started avoiding
my mother whenever possible.
What are you doing in there?
Keeping your secret.
You got to pull it together.
This is me pulling it together.
- Pull harder.
- Find 'em?
Yeah. Got 'em. Thanks.
You're very welcome.
Hey, have you noticed
anything off with Sheldon?
Uh, no, no, no.
Can't say that I have. Why?
He's been awful quiet,
and, at the risk of being indelicate,
he's gone several days
without a bowel movement.
How do you know that?
Well, I was worried about him,
so I took
a look in his potty journal.
He's still keeping that thing,
huh?
Oh, yeah, that's why
he wanted the Polaroid camera.
Uh, well,
I'm sure he's gonna be fine,
uh, but I'll keep an eye on him.
- Thank you.
- You got it.
- She's gone.
- Thank you.
Batteries are in this drawer.
We got a problem.
I don't know how much
longer Sheldon can hold out.
This is why I did not
want you to write a check.
Well, I'm sorry,
but I didn't have
that kind of cash lying around.
I do not want Mary
to find out about this.
Well, what about Sheldon?
The kid hasn't pooped
in days, he might pop.
Slip a little Metamucil
into his apple juice, he'll be fine.
Why don't we just
come clean?
All right, sure,
we could do that.
You could rat me out
to Mary and...
I could tell her
what you did at the church picnic.
Come on.
Now you're just playing dirty.
We sink or swim together,
George.
We sink or swim together.
Grandmas are supposed to be nice.
What went wrong with you?
Avoiding my mother
in our own house
was proving to be difficult,
so it was time to get creative.
Hello. I'd like to book
a room in your hotel.
I'd be arriving tonight.
No, it's just me.
Ooh, a queen bed,
that sounds fancy.
And how much would this room cost?
Wow. Is that per month?
Per day?
By any chance, do you
have a children's rate?
We've been friends for
a while now, haven't we?
I suppose so.
Given that, how would you
feel about a sleepover?
Sure.
Your mom lets you watch TV.
Jake and the Fatman is on tonight.
I meant we could sleep at
your house.
But you'll miss
Jake and the Fatman.
Even better.
So what do you say?
I'll have to ask my mom.
Well, be sure to tell her
I'm clean, I'm well-behaved,
and if you don't have a lot of room,
I can fit in really tight spaces.
So your first sleepover.
Pretty exciting, huh?
No. It's not exciting,
it's constipating,
and I'm only doing it
to avoid Mom.
But still,
it's your first sleepover.
It's fun stuff.
Okay, I know you're having
a tough time with this,
but...
you're doing great.
You spend some time at Tam's house,
you know, clear your head,
and come back home refreshed.
And then I can tell Mom?
Oh, no, you can never tell Mom.
Wouldn't it be easier
to just be honest?
Usually, it would be, but...
sometimes
the truth can hurt people.
We wouldn't want
to hurt Mom, right?
Of course not.
Attaboy.
Hey, here's a funny
prank you can try tonight.
When Tam falls asleep,
put some shaving cream in his hand
and then tickle his nose.
Why?
'Cause then he'll go to,
you know, scratch his nose,
and he gets shaving cream
on his face.
And then what?
Well... that-that's it.
But I'm a guest in their home,
and that doesn't seem
like a very good way
to repay their kindness.
Never mind.
And what if the shaving
cream gets in his eyes?
That would sting.
Sorry I mentioned it.
Also, I didn't bring
my own shaving cream.
I'd have to use his dad's, and that...
Forget it!
Hello.
Hi. You must be Mrs....
Tam's mom.
I'm Sheldon's dad, George Cooper.
Nice to meet you.
Thanks for letting him
spend the night.
It's his first sleepover.
He's excited.
Actually, I'm quite apprehens...
He's really looking forward to it.
Uh, in case something
comes up, just
give us a holler.
I mean, a call.
If you hollered,
we wouldn't hear you.
That-that was a joke.
Ha-ha-ha!
Okay, buddy, have fun.
Visiting Tam's house
for the first time was
an emotional roller coaster.
For example, it's traditional
in Vietnamese homes
to have gruesome religious
iconography near the entrance.
I did not like that.
However, it's also customary
to not wear shoes around the house
for sanitary reasons.
I did like that.
Interestingly,
one of the main ingredients
in Vietnamese cooking
is an extremely pungent
condiment known as fish sauce.
I did not like that.
But before every meal,
it's common for everyone
to wash their hands and face.
I did like that.
Forks are not customary
in a Vietnamese household.
I did not like that.
And instead of napkins,
there was one towel
for everyone
to share at the table.
Seriously, what are they thinking?
I can't help thinking how odd it is
that Shelly volunteered
to go on a sleepover.
Oh, I don't know.
Hmm? He's growing up.
It's natural for a young boy
to want to spread his wings
a little bit, try something new.
That's nonsense.
Last week, I brought home
the Raisin Bran with
the sugar on the raisins.
He almost lost his mind.
If you ask me,
you're worried about nothing.
Maybe it's me.
Maybe I did something
to upset him.
What are you talking about?
He loves you
like crazy.
Much more than
he loves this one.
It's true.
I don't know.
I just feel like
something isn't right.
Mom!
I got my hair stuck in my zipper!
That's the kid you need
to be worried about.
Okay, Connie, why don't
we just come clean?
- No.
- You heard her.
Now she's blaming herself.
And Sheldon's so upset
he's... he's acting
like a regular kid.
- All right, let's tell her.
- Thank you.
But first I'm gonna tell her
what you did at the picnic.
- Oh, Mary!
- Okay, okay, shh.
I don't know how much longer
we can keep this going.
I'm willing to find out.
So, this game is called
Mystic Warlords of Ka'a.
It's pretty fun.
There are six kinds
of secret warlords...
- Secret warlords.
- It's a secret. Secret.
It's a secret.
Have you noticed
anything off with Sheldon?
Something between me and you.
Mom is on a need-to-know basis.
I took a little look
in his potty journal.
- It's a secret.
- Several days without a bowel movement.
- Sheldon.
- Secret. Secret.
- A secret.
- Sheldon.
Did you hear anything I said?
Sorry, I was reliving
a traumatic experience.
What do you mean?
Tam, I have a secret
that's weighing on me,
and I need to tell someone.
Okay. Tell me.
But I promised I wouldn't.
Okay. Then don't.
But it's driving me crazy.
Too bad you're not Catholic.
You could confess it
to a priest.
That's a great idea.
You're Catholic.
I'll confess it to you.
I'm not a priest.
I'm not a Catholic.
It makes perfect sense.
Okay,
whenever you're ready.
What are you doing?
I'm assuming the position.
Okay.
Forgive me, Tam,
for I have sinned.
This is my first confession.
I forgive you, my son.
I was doing my parents' taxes
and noticed a check was missing.
- I asked my father about it...
- As I walked Tam
through the whole sordid affair,
I could feel a weight
lifting off my shoulders.
It was a relief to
finally unburden myself
of this deception.
By the time I reached the end,
I felt like a new person.
That's the whole story.
Cool. Can we play now?
And now that my conscience
had been cleared,
my colon was ready
to do the same.
Excuse me.
I need to use your bathroom!
Thank you for letting me
sleep in your bed.
My father taught me that
we must always honor our guests
and treat them
with the utmost courtesy.
The Vietnamese are
a very welcoming people.
Yeah,
that hasn't always worked out for us.
Do you think
your dad would ever ask you
to keep a secret
from your mom?
Oh, no.
He's so honest,
it's annoying.
Enough talking.
Sleep now.
She's just annoying.
Well, you did it.
How was your first sleepover?
They feed you any weird food?
When I was in 'Nam,
we ate fish soup for breakfast.
Sheldon, I'm talking to you.
Well, I'm not talking to you.
Okay, what's going on?
After having my first
good night's sleep in a week,
I woke up
with a fresh perspective.
And that is...?
It was irresponsible of you
to burden me with that secret.
Sheldon, we've been through this.
Okay. It's...
It's complicated.
While I may not look
up to you
from an intellectual
standpoint,
I've always looked up
to you as a role model.
I can't do that anymore.
And don't worry...
We made a deal.
I'll continue to keep your secret.
Hey.
What's up?
Um,
I need to tell you something.
What did you do?
When Sheldon was doing our taxes,
he noticed a missing check.
What did you do?
Before I answer,
do you trust me enough
to understand
it was for a good reason
and j-just leave it at that?
What did you do?
It's all your mother's fault.
She is a bad person.
I've been telling you for years.
What did you do?
Okay, now, before I answer that...
Just tell me what you did.
I got a DWI.
Mom!
It's not as bad as it sounds.
How is driving drunk not bad?
I wasn't exactly driving.
I don't follow.
I was at the dog track
with Georgie,
and I had a few...
Georgie?
With God as my witness,
I've never been to the
dog track in my life.
She knows.
Oh, I've been there a bunch.
Will someone please
tell me what happened?
Okay, me and Meemaw were
in the bar at the track...
You took him to a bar?
He wasn't drinking.
She had a few
too many margaritas,
so I drove us home.
But you don't have a license.
That's why we swapped places
after the cop pulled us over.
Oh, dear Lord.
I had nothing to do
with this part.
- Shut up.
- Will do.
I didn't want Georgie
to get into trouble,
so I got behind the wheel
before the cop walked up.
And then I got arrested, and, uh,
he bailed me out.
So you all thought
you should keep this from me?
- Absolutely.
- 100%.
Okay, here's
what's gonna happen: you
and you are staying at her house
until I say otherwise.
One could argue
I was the hero in this story.
You went gambling
and  you drove without a license
and you lied to my face.
Heroically.
Go.
I love everything
about this.
I'm guessing
you're mad at me.
Aw, forget about it.
I appreciate you not...
ratting me out
about the picnic.
Well, we had a deal.
Besides, your marriage
is already hanging by a thread.
It is dangling there.
All right, well,
I'm gonna turn in.
Mmm.
Good night.
Night!
Hello?
So, get a load of this.
Last church picnic,
your husband
snuck in a six-pack,
polished off
the whole thing,
then went to wait
in line for the bathroom...
Hey.
You got an extra toothbrush?
Under the sink, darlin'.
Thanks.
You got it.
So then the big gorilla decides
he doesn't want to wait in line,
so he stumbles over to
the church vegetable garden
and proceeds to irrigate
the whole damn thing.
I've eaten those vegetables.
Sweet dreams.